Michael W. Tishman, II

Website: https://tishinator.github.io/

Mike.tishman@gmail.com

Professional Summary:

Accomplished Software Engineer with a Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering and over 6 years of progressive experience in the industry. Proven track record in taking on diverse development roles and projects, showcasing a strong proficiency in Python and Javascript. Demonstrates a keen ability to adapt to new technologies, resolve vulnerabilities, and successfully manage and contribute to complex projects. Recognized for a strong ethic, dedication to task completion, and commitment to sharing knowledge and experiences within the team. Holds a TS security clearance.

Education:

Florida Institute of Technology Melbourne, FL

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering Graduated: May 2017

Skills:

Programming Languages: Python, Javascript, Java, C#, Fortran Databases: ElasticSearch, SQLite, MySQL

Software Tools:

Development Environments: Pycharm, Visual Studio, Eclipse

Version Control: Git, GitHub

Project and Issue Tracking: JIRA Continuous Integration: Jenkins

Security Clearance: TS (Current)

Experience:

Software Engineer III

ENSCO, Inc. | 2019 - Present

Location: Melbourne, FL

- Oversaw the development and expansion of Selenium Functional Tests for AIMS, configuring them for operation on Jenkins.
- Contributed as a software developer on the Spectre and G2S projects, writing Python code, mitigating vulnerabilities identified by SonarQube, and setting up a GeoServer server to operate with the SSL (HTTPS) protocol.
- Orchestrated the integration of ECM software within ENSCO's Restricted Area (RA), including the installation of MATLAB and Python, and the preparation of the customer's code for development.
- Actively participated in several AIMS development projects, catering to our Air Force customer's needs.
- Facilitated collaborative efforts, assisted in software deliveries, and allocated work to team members, ensuring project success.
- Supported team members in their tasks by sharing insights and lessons from previous projects, fostering a
 collaborative work environment.

Software Engineer II ENSCO, Inc.

| 2017-2019

Location: Melbourne, FL

- Became a key developer in various Seismic development teams, including G2S, ROSETTA, and CSAD providing both frontend and backend support for these projects.
- Contributed to the development of AIMS Incidents Master Source, Sampler List, and Source/Sampler Classification applications, demonstrating competence in Oracle SQL modifications, data export functionality, and GUI modifications.
- Took over initial builds for Python projects as part of ENSCO's goal to incorporate Python-based projects into the nightly/weekly build.
- Enhanced front-end user interface for the APACHE project, garnering positive feedback from project leads and clients.

Software Development / Software Testing Intern ENSCO Inc.

|2016 - 2017|

Location: Melbourne, FL

- Designed and programmed automated regression test for various ENSCO Applications.
- Converted and updated older tests to accommodate newer software testing tools.

Software Development Intern

Netboss Technologies, Inc

|2015 - 2015|

Location: Sebastian, FL

- Integrated a new functionality into Netboss's Self-Monitoring system that provides a simple way to monitor customer data.
- Designed a Java server/client application that receives and formats data from mail servers, and stores that data into an ElasticSearch Database.
- Wrote a Javascript web interface to display data from an ElasticSearch database using Google-Map APIs.

Software Engineer

8th Domain Technology, LLC

|2014 - 2014|

Location: Coral Springs, FL

• Designed a VB.NET / Visual C# Windows-Form desktop application for a Chiropractic business to allow them to have a paperless record keeping system.